#### Sorocaba, São Paulo, Brazil •

henrique.rodrigues7@hotmail.com •

Phone: +55 (11) 97190-8333 •

https://henriquerod.com/ •

https://www.linkedin.com/in/henrique-rodrigues7/ •

https://github.com/henrique945 •

# Henrique Rodrigues Silva

Full Stack Engineer and Techlead

#### OBJECTIVE ·····

Software Engineer with +5 years of experience leading a group of more than 20 people (techlead) and developed more than 40 software, including websites, apps and systems (apis), who values working in healthy environments with good communication and trust. I look for more development and learning challenges. I am able to work under pressure with many people and in dynamic environments with high context switching. Currently working on INDRASOL - ICANotes, an US based company.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# **Software Engineer**

INDRASOL - ICANotes, Sep 2023 - Now

Indrasol Solution, a global provider of consulting, implementation and support services of Oracle solution.

- Worked on Icanotes project, US target audience, a behavioral health EHR that specializes in faster note-taking for therapists, psychiatrists, psychologists.
- Convert files from American insurance companies (Electronic Remittance Advice) in the billing team to claims and payments.
- Coding using Angular, NodeJs, HTML5, CSS3, Jasper, MySQL and Typescript.
- Services designed and implemented within AWS.
- Web development software with SCRUM, git (version control system) and CI/CD integrations.

# **Software Engineer**

Dev.Pro, Mar 2023 - Sep 2023

Dev.Pro, a global software development partner based in the US.

- Worked on the Xenial Data Management Could project, a Global Payments Company.
- My team was working on data management for companies like Taco Bell and Burger King.
- Developed some receipt email templates for CosMc's, a McDonald's company.
- Coding using Angular, NodeJs, MongoDB and Javascript/Typescript and Aws Cloud integrated with CI/CD.
- Whole system coverage with unit tests, e2e tests and integration tests.

### **Full-Stack Developer**

Liga - Facens, July 2019 - Mar 2023

Liga Facens, a Brazilian software house company, that I had +4 years of experience.

- Mobile apps built with Ionic, Angular / ReactJs (HTML5 and CSS3 / SASS) and Typescript (Javascript) for a variety of businesses and government organizations.
- REST APIs architectured in NestJS (NodeJs) using PostgresSQL / Sqlite / MySQL / MongoDB for deployment within AWS using AWS Lambda and integrating with services such as S3, Api Gateway, SQS, SNS, SES, Cloudfront.
- Services designed and implemented within AWS.
- Created classes to teach and integrate new members to the dev team.
- PWA and web development software with SCRUM, kanban and git (version control system).
- Integrations with Google Maps, MaterialUI, Bootstrap, Leaflet, Capacitor and other external APIs and systems.

## **EDUCATION**

## **Bachelor of Computer Engineering**

Facens - "Faculdade de Engenharia de Sorocaba" 2018 - 2022

## ADDITIONAL SKILLS .....

- Ability to lead and communicate with your team
- Ability to solve various problems
- Ability of managing multiple projects and handling pressure
- Ability of mentoring other developers with pair-programming and code-review
- Participated in the NASA Simulation Exploration Experience project
- Exchange program to Austria to improve English
- Volunteer at Lions Clubs International for over 8 years

#### PROJECTS (more projects at: https://henriquerod.com/)

- **Ecologicatech** Developed in Angular (HTML, SASS, Typescript) and NestJs (NodeJs + PostgresSQL) with AWS Cloud (Aws Lambda + S3) and integrated with Google Maps API. Ecologicatech was developed for Aguama, environmental management and marketing company, the project focused on the creation of events for companies and on replies to these events forms, with this data we can calculate the distance between locations and transport (using Google Maps API). And verify the amount of CO2 emitted on the planet. Thus knowing how many trees will be needed to combat the CO2 emitted <a href="https://henriquerod.com/project/ecologicatech">https://henriquerod.com/project/ecologicatech</a>.
- ABB Developed in Angular (HTML, SASS, Typescript) and accessing AWS S3 with AWS Cloud (Aws Lambda + S3). Site to download the most recent Virtual Reality training from the multinational company ABB that works in energy and automation technologies. It is possible to switch between 3 different languages (EN, ES, PT) and download the apk of approximately 1gb to be played on the VR glasses using the AWS S3 file container <a href="https://henriquerod.com/project/abb">https://henriquerod.com/project/abb</a>.
- **Terrex** Developed in Ionic/Angular (HTML, SASS, Typescript) and NestJs (NodeJs + PostgresSQL) with AWS Cloud (Aws Lambda + S3) and integrated with plugfield and foreca. Project where a farmer delimits his land by GPS or drawing on a map and chooses the planting cycles that will be planted, developed for Tecnomyl (Brasil Distribuidora de Produtos Agrícolas Ltda). Their plots are equipped with Plugfield robots that measure toxins and soil water temperature/density together with foreca weather and cloud api. In addition to a wonderful interface and several functionalities about your crop cycle and terrain, there is a routine in the Aws (Event Bridge) to periodically send notifications to the user about instructions necessary for your plantation to remain healthy https://henriquerod.com/project/terrex.
- Zoo PZMQB Developed in Ionic/Angular (HTML, SASS, Typescript) using WebAnimationJs, PinchZoomJs, Leaflet for maps and integrated with QR Code. Project developed for the Zoo PZMQB for children to have fun and learn more about animals. We have an integrated missions system with QrCode spread over several animals in the zoo and as a reward for the missions, each user gets a sticker and can complete their virtual album and win prizes. Besides all information, events and stories about the zoo and the animals <a href="https://henriquerod.com/project/zoo">https://henriquerod.com/project/zoo</a>.
- Poliedro P+ Kids Developed in NestJs (NodeJs + PostgresSQL + MongoDB) with Poliedro APIs. App for Poliedro students and guardians
  that allows access to school information such as schedule, gradebook, messages, tasks, resolutions of material and performance in
  simulations, with feedback and performance analysis. It is organized, easy and practical and has more than 100,000 accesses <a href="https://henriquerod.com/project/poliedro">https://henriquerod.com/project/poliedro</a>.
- Falai Developed in Ionic/Angular (HTML, SASS, Typescript) and integrated with Leaflet (map + geosearch + markercluster) library for Maps. Falai was developed for the city of Sorocaba in partnership with SPLICE (SpliceGroup provides a wide-range of end-to-end fibre connectivity solutions helping to connect organizations, homes and people around the globe) and sold to several cities. Within the app, the citizen can open and control requests about the city's problems, focused on integrating the system with city maps, being able to search for your street and group your created requests <a href="https://henriquerod.com/project/falai">https://henriquerod.com/project/falai</a>.
- **Proton** Developed in Ionic/Angular (HTML, SASS, Typescript) as an App and a PWA and NestJs (NodeJs + PostgresSQL) with AWS Cloud (Aws Lambda + S3) and integrated with Apple and Facebook login and with support of RSS Feed. App developed for the users to be able to navigate between their news focused on the financial market at the request of the client Carol Paiffer (Shark Tank) ATOM S/A. The news was dynamically updated by the Aws routine (Event Bridge) based on RSS feeds from notifiers such as BBC, Globo and Uol. The user could read, comment, like and save the news for later <a href="https://henriquerod.com/project/proton">https://henriquerod.com/project/proton</a>.
- Mundo SBT Developed in Angular (HTML, SASS, Typescript) and Javascript function API with AWS Cloud (Aws Lambda + S3) and integrated with Microsoft PlayFab. A website developed for SBT Games, a sector of the SBT TV station that talks about game news. Site for password recovery and user email confirmation on first access to the Mundo SBT RPG game running with Microsoft PlayFab <a href="https://henriquerod.com/project/mundoSbt">https://henriquerod.com/project/mundoSbt</a>.
- Facens Developed in Ionic/Angular (HTML, SASS, Typescript) and NestJs (NodeJs + PostgresSQL) with AWS Cloud (Aws Lambda + S3) and integrated with Facens authentication system. With the FACENS app you can view your grades, absences and class schedules. In addition, you will be able to interact with FACENS events using a single application and access your student ID card <a href="https://henriquerod.com/project/facens">https://henriquerod.com/project/facens</a>.